

Hilal Ahmad

Date of birth: 25/12/1995 | Nationality: Pakistani | Gender: Male | Phone number: (+90) 5525677164 (Mobile) |

Email address: hilahmad.civilengineer@gmail.com | Instagram: https://www.instagram.com/hil.ahm/ |

Address: Yeni Hatay Stadyum, Hatay, Türkiye (Work)

ABOUT ME

I am Hilal Ahmad, I graduated from Yozgat Bozok University as a **Civil Engineer**, currently doing my **Masters in Architecture** at Istanbul Altınbaş University. From 8th February to this day, I have been working in the Humanitarian sector. Previously I worked in a **Shelter Container**, **toilet and shower Manufacturing Company** as an **AutoCAD drafter**, SEO expert **(Data Analyst)** and **Web developer** and later in an education consultant agency as a web developer. My skills are,

Softwares

• Microsoft Office, AutoCAD

Trainings

 ActivityInfo & Services Advisor, PSEA Capacity Building Training, Core Humanitarian Standard training, National NGO Program on Humanitarian Leadership course (Upcoming)

Tools

 Activity Info, Google Keyword Planner, Google Trend, Google Search Console, Google Analytics, Ahref SEMrush, MOZ, Ubbersugest

Programming

• Javascript, Python, C++, React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Languages

• Urdu or Hindi English Turkish German Arabic French

WORK EXPERIENCE

17/03/2023 - CURRENT HATAY, Türkiye

MEAL ASSISTANT YARDIM KONVOYU İNSANI YARDIM DAYANISMA VE KALKINMA DERNEĞI

- Going to the field and doing **need assessment**. Preparing, Monitoring, and participating in **FSL**, **Shelter & NFI**, and **WASH** activities, Preparing Activity reports, and also preparing **maps** related to our NGO's activities.
- Attending regularly WASH, FSL, and Early Recovery **(ER)** which is now Economic Empowerment **(EE)** meetings.
- Participating in sector-related courses (The Wash Systom Academy by **IRC** and Humanitarian Leadership Academy by **Kaya**) and attending sector-related training.

27/02/2023 - 31/08/2023 HATAY, Türkiye

KITCHEN PROJECT COORDINATOR BELGIUM AID (BELGIUM), FEEDING HUMANITY (UK) AND MÜSLÜMAN ELLER DERNEĞI (TÜRKIYE)

- Set up a **temporary kitchen** next to the **formal tent campsite** in the Samandağ-Hatay area.
- Set up a cooking, depo, and Food serving area with the help of the **Turkish Army**.
- Talked with the **AFAD**, **Kızılay** for the delivery of kitchen items and also talked with the **governing bodies** of Samandağ district for the supply of water and electricity and was delivering **4000** meals per/day.
- Talked with the **local and international media** to explain our efforts to deliver food to the locals.
- Worked as a **Translator** with doctors from the UK and USA.
- Engaged with the **local communities**, trying to solve their problems, and delivering them the right information which I got from the sector meetings.
- Set up a **playing area** for the kids with the help of locals and volunteers, where we arranged entertainment activities for the kids living in the formal tent campsite.

08/02/2023 - 16/02/2023 HATAY, Türkiye

SEARCH AND RESCUE TEAM MEMBER ANDA | EĞITIM ARAŞTIRMA YARDIMLAŞMA VE ARAMA KURTARMA DERNEĞI

- Participated in Rescue operations near **Ronessans Residence** area in Antakya.
- Worked as a **Translator** with international rescue teams.
- Worked as a **Civil engineer** by leading rescue teams and also **drawing sketches** of the affected structures to find the location of the staircases and lift areas, because most of the people lost their lives in these areas.

02/02/2022 - 27/10/2022 Istanbul, Türkiye

AUTOCAD DRAFTER, SEARCH ENGINE OPTIMISATION EXPERT (DATA ANALYST) AND WEB DEVELOPER. WORLD SEVEN PREFABRIK YAPI SANAYI VE TICARET LIMITED ŞIRKETI

In this work experience, I get the experience of working in different fields.

- I started my job as a **Front-End Web developer**. I built the first version of **containhaus.de** using **React js** and **Next js**.
- My second work experience was there as a **Search Engine Optimization Expert** (SEO). I was doing the SEO especially for the **German marketplace** and in the general overall European marketplace.
- My last work experience in the company was to draw **AutoCAD** drawings of **shelter containers**, **toilets**, **and shower cabins with sanitation facilities** and also customize them according to the needs of customers.

Note: Because of this experience I became an expert in **container-based shelter design and manufacturing** which is one of the most essential needs of the shelter sector for the longer term.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

15/10/2022 - CURRENT Istanbul, Türkiye

MSC ARCHITECTURE Altinbaş University Istanbul

Website www.altinbas.edu.tr

15/09/2016 - 07/02/2021 Yozgat, Türkiye

CIVIL ENGINEER Yozgat Bozok University

Website www.bozok.edu.tr

01/02/2020 - 30/04/2020 Lahore, Pakistan

AUTOCAD TRAINING COURSE Digiskills.pk

Website digiskills.pk

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **URDU** | **PANJABI; PUNJABI**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C2	C2	C1	C1	C1
TURKISH	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
GERMAN	B1	B1	B1	B1	B1
ARABIC	A1	A1	A1	A1	A1
FRENCH	A1	A1	A1	A1	A1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user